<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    
    <!-- PriesthoodOrdinances Manifest -->
    <string name="app_name">LDS Ordinances</string>
    
    <!-- Titles used in MainMenu -->
    <string name="AnointingOil">Anointing with Oil</string>
    <string name="SealingAnointing">Sealing the Anointing</string>
    <string name="ConsecratingOil">Consecrating Oil</string>
    <string name="ConferringPriesthood">Conferring the Priesthood and Offices</string>
    <string name="SettingApart">Setting Apart Officers and Teachers</string>
	<string name="FatherBlessing">Father’s/Comforting Blessing</string>
	<string name="NamingChildren">Naming and Blessing Children</string>
	<string name="Baptism">Baptism</string>
	<string name="Confirmation">Confirmation</string>
	<string name="Sacrament">Sacrament</string>
	<string name="DedicatingHomes">Dedicating Homes</string>
	<string name="DedicatingGraves">Dedicating Graves</string>
	
	<!-- CAB text used in MainMenu -->
	<string name="select_items">Select Ordinance</string>
	<string name="cant_move_up">Can\'t move top ordinance up</string>
	<string name="moved_up">Ordinance moved up</string>
	<string name="moved_up_plural">Ordinances moved up</string>
	<string name="cant_move_down">Can\'t move bottom ordinance down</string>
	<string name="moved_down">Ordinance moved down</string>
	<string name="moved_down_plural">Ordinances moved down</string>
	<string name="one_selected">1 Ordinance selected</string>
	<string name="items_selected">Ordinances selected</string>
	
	
	<!-- Text used to fill content in blessings.xml and Ordinance.java -->
    <string name="anointing_oil">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Anointing with Oil</b></p>
        
	        <p>The anointing is done by one Melchizedek Priesthood holder. He:</p>
			
			<b>1.</b> Puts a drop of consecrated oil on the person’s head.<br />
			<b>2.</b> Places his hands lightly on the person’s head and calls the person by his or her full name.<br />
			<b>3.</b> States that he is anointing the person by the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood.<br />
			<b>4.</b> States that he is anointing with oil that has been consecrated for anointing and blessing the sick and afflicted.<br />
			<b>5.</b> Closes in the name of Jesus Christ.
			
        
        	<p><b>Administering to the Sick</b></p>
			
			<p>Only men who hold the Melchizedek Priesthood may administer to the sick or afflicted. 
			Normally, two or more administer together, but one may do it alone. If consecrated oil 
			is not available, a man who holds the Melchizedek Priesthood may give a blessing by the 
			authority of the priesthood.</p>
			
			<p>A father who holds the Melchizedek Priesthood normally should administer to sick members of 
			his family.</p>
        	
        	<p>Brethren should administer to the sick at the request of the sick person or of those
        	who are vitally concerned so the blessing will be according to their faith (see 
        	<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/24.13-14?lang=eng#13">D&amp;C 24:13-14</a>,
        	<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.43-44?lang=eng#43">42:43-44</a>,
        	<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.48-52?lang=eng#48"> 48-52</a>).
        	Melchizedek Priesthood holders who visit hospitals should not solicit opportunities to administer to the sick.</p>
        	
        	<p>If a person requests more than one blessing for the same illness, the priesthood holder need 
        	not anoint with oil after the first blessing. Instead, he gives a blessing by the laying on of 
        	hands and the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood.</p>

			<p>Administering to the sick has two parts: anointing with oil and sealing the anointing.</p>
        	
		]]>
    </string>
    
    <string name="sealing_anointing">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Sealing the Anointing</b></p>
        
	        <p>The one who seals the anointing:</p>
			
			<b>1.</b> Calls the person by his or her full name.<br />
			<b>2.</b> States that he is sealing the anointing by the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood.<br />
			<b>3.</b> Gives a blessing as the Spirit directs.<br />
			<b>4.</b> Closes in the name of Jesus Christ.
			
			<p>Normally, two or more men who hold the Melchizedek Priesthood place their hands lightly on the 
			head of the person who is sick.<p>
        
        	<p><b>Administering to the Sick</b></p>
			
			<p>Only men who hold the Melchizedek Priesthood may administer to the sick or afflicted. 
			Normally, two or more administer together, but one may do it alone. If consecrated oil 
			is not available, a man who holds the Melchizedek Priesthood may give a blessing by the 
			authority of the priesthood.</p>
			
			<p>A father who holds the Melchizedek Priesthood normally should administer to sick members of 
			his family.</p>
        	
        	<p>Brethren should administer to the sick at the request of the sick person or of those
        	who are vitally concerned so the blessing will be according to their faith (see 
        	<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/24.13-14?lang=eng#13">D&amp;C 24:13-14</a>,
        	<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.43-44?lang=eng#43">42:43-44</a>,
        	<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.48-52?lang=eng#48"> 48-52</a>).
        	Melchizedek Priesthood holders who visit hospitals should not solicit opportunities to administer to the sick.</p>
        	
        	<p>If a person requests more than one blessing for the same illness, the priesthood holder need 
        	not anoint with oil after the first blessing. Instead, he gives a blessing by the laying on of 
        	hands and the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood.</p>

			<p>Administering to the sick has two parts: anointing with oil and sealing the anointing.</p>
		]]>
    </string>
    
    <string name="consecrating_anointing">        
        <![CDATA[
        	
        	<p><b>Consecrating Oil</b></p>
        
	        <p>To consecrate oil, a priesthood holder:</p>
			
			<b>1.</b> Holds an open container of olive oil.<br />
			<b>2.</b> Addresses our Heavenly Father.<br />
			<b>3.</b> States that he is acting by the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood.<br />
			<b>4.</b> Consecrates the oil (not the container) and sets it apart for anointing and 
			blessing of the sick and afflicted.<br />
			<b>5.</b> Closes in the name of Jesus Christ.
        
        	<p>One or more Melchizedek Priesthood holders must consecrate olive oil before it is 
        	used to anoint the sick or afflicted. No other oil may be used.</p>
        	
        	<p>Members should not take consecrated oil internally or apply it on afflicted parts of the body.</p>
        
		]]>
    </string>
    
    <string name="conferring_priesthood">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Conferring the Priesthood and Ordaining to an Office</b></p>
        
	        <p>The priesthood holder who performs the ordination:</p>
			
			<b>1.</b> Calls the person by his full name.<br />
			<b>2.</b> States the authority by which the ordination is performed (Aaronic or Melchizedek Priesthood).<br />
			<b>3.</b> Confers the Aaronic or Melchizedek Priesthood, unless it has already been conferred.<br />
			<b>4.</b> Ordains the person to an office in the Aaronic or Melchizedek Priesthood and bestows 
			the rights, powers, and authority of that office. (Priesthood keys are not bestowed in conferring 
			the priesthood or ordaining to one of these offices.)<br />
			<b>5.</b> Gives words of blessing as the Spirit directs.<br />
			<b>6.</b> Closes in the name of Jesus Christ.
			
			<p>To perform a priesthood ordination, one or more authorized priesthood holders place their hands 
			lightly on the person’s head.</p>
			
			<p>When the necessary interviews and approvals are completed:</p>

			<p>1. The stake president (or someone under his direction) may ordain the person to the 
			office of elder, or he may authorize another Melchizedek Priesthood holder to do so. 
			Only Melchizedek Priesthood holders may stand in the circle.</p>
			
			<p>2. The stake president (or someone under his direction) may ordain the person to the 
			office of high priest, or he may authorize another high priest to do so. Only high priests 
			may stand in the circle.</p>
			
			<p>3. The bishop (or someone under his direction) may ordain the person to the office of 
			deacon, teacher, or priest. Only priests and Melchizedek Priesthood holders may act as 
			voice or stand in the circle.</p>
			
			<p>To participate in an ordination, a person must (1) be a priest or Melchizedek Priesthood 
			holder and (2) have equal or higher priesthood authority than is to be given in the ordinance. 
			For instance, an elder should not stand in the circle when a high priest is ordained or when 
			a man is set apart to an office that requires him to be a high priest.</p>
        
		]]>
    </string>
    
    
    <string name="setting_appart">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Setting Apart Officers and Teachers</b></p>
        
	        <p>The priesthood holder who acts as voice:</p>
			
			<b>1.</b> Calls the person by his or her full name.<br />
			<b>2.</b> States that he is acting by the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood.<br />
			<b>3.</b> Sets the person apart to the appropriate office in the stake, ward, quorum, high 
			priests group, or class.<br />
			<b>4.</b> Confers keys if the person is entitled to receive them. (In stakes and wards, only 
			stake presidents, bishops, and quorum presidents receive keys of presidency when they are set 
			apart. The word keys should not be used when setting apart counselors, high councilors, high 
			priests group leaders, presidents of auxiliary organizations, the bishop’s priests quorum 
			assistants, or teachers in an organization.)<br />
			<b>5.</b> Gives words of blessing as the Spirit directs.<br />
			<b>6.</b> Closes in the name of Jesus Christ.
			
			<p>Under the direction of the presiding authority, one or more Melchizedek Priesthood holders 
			may participate in a setting apart, including a worthy father or husband. These brethren 
			place their hands lightly on the person’s head.</p>
			
			<p>Members who are called to most Church positions should be set apart before they begin 
			serving. The Chart of Callings indicates who is authorized to perform a setting apart. Presidents 
			are set apart before their counselors.</p>
			
			<p>A setting apart is an opportunity to give a blessing. Detailed counsel and instruction are 
			normally provided when a person is taught his or her duties rather than during the setting apart.</p>
			
			<p>A setting apart should not be expanded into a formal meeting. It is not necessary to have 
			prayers, testimonies, or instruction when someone is set apart.</p>
        
		]]>
    </string>
    
    
    <string name="father_blessings">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Father’s Blessings and Other Blessings of Comfort and Counsel</b></p>
        
	        <p>The priesthood holder who gives the blessing:</p>
			
			<b>1.</b> Calls the person by his or her full name.<br />
			<b>2.</b> States that he is giving the blessing by the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood.<br />
			<b>3.</b> Gives a blessing as the Spirit directs.<br />
			<b>4.</b> Closes in the name of Jesus Christ.
			
			<p>To give a father’s blessing or another blessing of comfort and counsel, one or more Melchizedek 
			Priesthood holders place their hands lightly on the person’s head.</p>
			
			<p>Father’s blessings and other priesthood blessings are given to provide direction and 
			comfort as guided by the Spirit.<p>
        
        	<p>A father who holds the Melchizedek Priesthood may give father’s blessings to his children. 
        	Such blessings may be especially helpful when children go away from home, such as to attend 
        	school or go on missions, or when they begin employment, get married, enter military service, 
        	or face unusual personal challenges. These blessings can be a great strength to a family. A 
        	family may record a father’s blessing for family records, but it is not preserved in Church 
        	records. Parents should encourage children to seek father’s blessings in times of need.</p>
        	
        	<p>Melchizedek Priesthood holders may also give blessings of comfort and counsel to other 
        	family members and to others who ask for them.</p>
        
		]]>
    </string>
    
    <string name="blessing_children">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Naming and Blessing Children</b></p>
        
	        <p>The person who gives the blessing:</p>
			
			<b>1.</b> Addresses Heavenly Father.<br />
			<b>2.</b> States that the blessing is given by the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood.<br />
			<b>3.</b> Gives the child a name.<br />
			<b>4.</b> Gives words of blessing as the Spirit directs.<br />
			<b>5.</b> Closes in the name of Jesus Christ.
			
			<p>When blessing a baby, men who hold the Melchizedek Priesthood gather in a circle and hold 
			the baby in their hands. When blessing an older child, brethren place their hands lightly on 
			the child’s head.<p>
        
        	<p>“Every member of the church of Christ having children is to bring them unto the elders before 
        	the church, who are to lay their hands upon them in the name of Jesus Christ, and bless them in 
        	his name” (<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.70?lang=eng#70">D&amp;C 20:70</a>). 
        	In conformity with this revelation, only Melchizedek Priesthood holders may participate in 
        	naming and blessing children. Priesthood leaders should inform members of this instruction before 
        	their children are named and blessed. While preserving the sacred nature of the blessing, leaders 
        	should make every reasonable effort to avoid embarrassment or offense to individuals or families.</p>
        
        	<p>Children are normally named and blessed during fast and testimony meeting in the ward where 
        	the parents are members of record.</p>
        	
        	<p>Before a child is blessed, the ward clerk prepares a Child Blessing Record. After the blessing, 
        	the clerk ensures that this form is complete, and he processes or distributes it according to 
        	instructions with the form. The clerk also prepares a blessing certificate. The bishop signs the 
        	certificate, and he or the clerk gives it to the child’s parent(s) or guardian(s).</p>
			
			<p>If a baby is born out of wedlock, the name on the membership record and certificate of blessing 
			should match the name on the birth certificate or civil birth registry. If a birth certificate or 
			civil birth registry does not exist, the naming conventions of the local culture are used.</p>
			        	
		]]>
    </string>
    
    <string name="baptism">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Baptism</b></p>
        
	        <p>The person performing the ordinance:</p>
			
			<b>1.</b> Stands in the water with the person to be baptized.<br />
			<b>2.</b> Holds the person’s right wrist with his left hand (for convenience and safety); 
			the person who is being baptized holds the priesthood holder’s left wrist with his or 
			her left hand.<br />
			<b>3.</b> Raises his right arm to the square.<br />
			<b>4.</b> States the person’s full name and says, “Having been commissioned of Jesus Christ, 
			I baptize you in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost. Amen” 
			(<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.73?lang=eng#73">D&amp;C 20:73</a>).<br />
			<b>5.</b> Has the person hold his or her nose with the right hand (for convenience); 
			then the priesthood holder places his right hand high on the person’s back and immerses 
			the person completely, including the person’s clothing.<br />
			<b>6.</b> Helps the person come up out of the water.
			
			<p><i>Under the direction of the presiding authority,</i> a worthy priest or man who holds the Melchizedek 
			Priesthood may perform a baptism. <p>
        
        	<p>Convert baptisms are usually performed by a priesthood holder in the ward or by one of the 
        	missionaries who taught the person. A convert may also request that another qualified member 
        	perform the baptism.</p>
        
		]]>
    </string>
    
    <string name="confirmation">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Confirmation</b></p>
        
	        <p>The person performing the ordinance:</p>
			
			<b>1.</b> States the person’s full name.<br />
			<b>2.</b> States that the ordinance is performed by the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood.<br />
			<b>3.</b> Confirms the person a member of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.<br />
			<b>4.</b> Uses the words “Receive the Holy Ghost” (not “receive the gift of the Holy Ghost”).<br />
			<b>5.</b> Gives a priesthood blessing as the Spirit directs.<br />
			<b>6.</b> Closes in the name of Jesus Christ.
			
			<p>A person is confirmed a member of the Church and receives the gift of the Holy Ghost after 
			being baptized (see 
			<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.41?lang=eng#41">D&amp;C 20:41</a>). 
			A person becomes a member of the Church only after the ordinances of baptism and confirmation 
			are both completed and properly recorded (see 
			<a href="https://www.lds.org/scriptures/nt/john/3.5?lang=eng#4">John 3:5</a>; 
			<a href="https://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/33.11?lang=eng#10">D&amp;C 33:11</a>).</p>
			
			<p>The bishop holds the keys for confirming 8-year-old members of record. The mission president 
			holds the keys for confirming converts. However, the bishop oversees the performance of this 
			ordinance, whether it is for an 8-year-old member of record or a convert. The bishop ensures 
			that it is performed soon after baptism.</p>
			
			<p>Eight-year-old members of record may be confirmed at the baptismal service or in a sacrament 
			meeting in the ward where they live, preferably a fast and testimony meeting.</p>
			
			<p>Converts are confirmed in any sacrament meeting in the ward where they live, preferably on 
			the Sunday following their baptism. Converts are not confirmed at the baptismal service.</p>
			
			<p>At least one member of the bishopric participates in this ordinance. When missionary elders 
			have taught a convert, the bishop should invite them to participate.</p>
			
			<p>The bishop does not conduct a separate interview for this ordinance.</p>
        
		]]>
    </string>
    
    <string name="dedicating_graves">
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Dedicating Graves</b></p>
        
	        <p>The person performing the ordinance:</p>
			
			<b>1.</b> Addresses Heavenly Father.<br />
			<b>2.</b> States that he is acting by the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood.<br />
			<b>3.</b> Dedicates and consecrates the burial plot as the resting place for the body of the deceased.<br />
			<b>4.</b> Prays that the place will be hallowed and protected until the Resurrection (where appropriate).<br />
			<b>5.</b> Asks the Lord to comfort the family and expresses other thoughts as the Spirit directs.<br />
			<b>6.</b> Closes in the name of Jesus Christ.
			
			<p>A person who dedicates a grave must hold the Melchizedek Priesthood and <i>must be authorized by the 
			priesthood officer who conducts the service.</i></p>
        
        	<p>If the family prefers, a graveside prayer rather than a dedicatory prayer may be offered.</p>
			
			<p>If a Church member’s body is cremated, the presiding officer may use his judgment in 
			determining whether to dedicate the place where the ashes are kept. He takes into account 
			the desires of the family, local customs, and local laws. If the place is dedicated, the 
			priesthood holder may adapt the instructions for dedicating a grave.</p>
        
		]]>
    </string>
    
    
    <string name="dedicating_homes">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Dedicating Homes</b></p>
        
	        <p>Church members may dedicate their homes as sacred edifices where the Holy Spirit can reside 
	        and where family members can worship, find safety from the world, grow spiritually, and prepare 
	        for eternal family relationships. Homes need not be free of debt to be dedicated. Unlike Church 
	        buildings, homes are not consecrated to the Lord.</p>

			<p>A Melchizedek Priesthood holder may dedicate a home by the power of the priesthood. If there 
			is not a Melchizedek Priesthood holder in the home, a family might invite a close relative, a 
			home teacher, or another Melchizedek Priesthood holder to dedicate the home. Or a family might 
			gather and offer a prayer that includes the elements mentioned in the preceding paragraph and 
			other words as the Spirit directs.</p>
        
		]]>
    </string>
    
    
    <string name="sacrament">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>Sacrament</b></p>
        
	        <p><b>Blessing the bread</b></p>
	        
	        <p>“O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee in the name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and 
	        sanctify this bread to the souls of all those who partake of it, that they may eat in remembrance 
	        of the body of thy Son, and witness unto thee, O God, the Eternal Father, that they are willing 
	        to take upon them the name of thy Son, and always remember him and keep his commandments which 
	        he has given them; that they may always have his Spirit to be with them. Amen” (
			<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77?lang=eng#77">D&amp;C 20:77</a> and 
			<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/bofm/moro/4.1-3?lang=eng">Moroni 4</a>).<p>
	        
	        <p><b>Blessing the water</b></p>
			
			<p>“O God, the Eternal Father, we ask thee in the name of thy Son, Jesus Christ, to bless and 
			sanctify this [water] to the souls of all those who drink of it, that they may do it in 
			remembrance of the blood of thy Son, which was shed for them; that they may witness unto thee, 
			O God, the Eternal Father, that they do always remember him, that they may have his Spirit to be 
			with them. Amen” 
			(<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.79?lang=eng#79">D&amp;C 20:79</a> and 
			<a href="http://www.lds.org/scriptures/bofm/moro/5.1-2?lang=eng">Moroni 5</a>).</p>
        
        	<p>Priests and Melchizedek Priesthood holders may bless the sacrament. Deacons, teachers, priests, 
        	and Melchizedek Priesthood holders may pass the sacrament.</p>
			
			<p>As the congregation sings the sacrament hymn, the priesthood holders who will bless the sacrament 
			reverently stand, remove the cloth that covers the bread trays, and break the bread into bite-sized 
			pieces. When they finish breaking the bread, they sit down and join in singing the hymn. Vocal solos 
			or instrumental music may not replace this hymn.</p>
			
			<p>Following the hymn, the person who blesses the bread kneels and offers the sacrament prayer for 
			the bread. The bishop 
			makes sure they are spoken clearly, accurately, and with dignity. If the person who blesses the 
			sacrament makes an error in the wording but corrects it himself, no further correction is required. 
			If the person does not correct an error, the bishop indicates that he should repeat the prayer correctly. 
			In doing so, the bishop should be careful to avoid causing embarrassment or distracting from the 
			sacred nature of the ordinance.</p>
			
			<p>After the prayer, deacons or other priesthood holders pass the bread to the congregation in a 
			reverent and orderly manner. The presiding officer receives the sacrament first. The bishop (or a 
			counselor in his absence) presides at the sacrament meeting unless a member of the stake presidency, 
			an Area Seventy, or a General Authority is sitting on the stand. A high councilor does not preside 
			and does not receive the sacrament first.</p>
			
			<p>While the presiding officer is receiving the sacrament, others who are passing the sacrament may 
			walk to their designated places.</p>
			
			<p>After a priesthood holder hands a sacrament tray to a member, others may pass the tray from one 
			to another for convenience.</p>
			
			<p>When brethren finish passing the bread, they return the trays to the sacrament table. Those 
			officiating at the sacrament table place the cloth over the bread trays and uncover the water trays. 
			The person who blesses the water then kneels and offers the sacrament prayer for the water, 
			substituting the word water for wine.</p>
			
			<p>After the prayer, deacons or other priesthood holders pass the water to the congregation. When 
			they finish, they return the trays to the sacrament table, wait for the officiators to cover the trays, 
			then reverently take their seats.</p>
			
			<p>Everyone who attends the meeting should be reverent during the entire ordinance of blessing and 
			passing the sacrament.</p>
			
			<p>No music should be played during the prayer, while the sacrament is being passed, or as a postlude 
			after the sacrament is passed.</p>


		]]>
    </string>
    
    <string name="blessings_in_general">        
        <![CDATA[
        
        	<p><b>General Instructions</b></p>
        
	        <p>An ordinance is a sacred act, such as baptism, that is performed by the authority of the priesthood. 
	        The ordinances of baptism, confirmation, Melchizedek Priesthood ordination (for men), the temple endowment, 
	        and temple sealing are required for exaltation for all accountable persons. These are called the saving 
	        ordinances. As part of each saving ordinance, the recipient makes covenants with God.</p>

			<p>Performance of a saving ordinance requires authorization from a priesthood leader who holds the appropriate 
			keys or who functions under the direction of a person who holds those keys. Such authorization is also required 
			for naming and blessing a child, dedicating a grave, giving a patriarchal blessing, and preparing, blessing, 
			and passing the sacrament. Melchizedek Priesthood holders may consecrate oil, administer to the sick, give 
			father’s blessings, and give other blessings of comfort and counsel without first seeking authorization from 
			a priesthood leader.</p>

			<p>Brethren who perform ordinances and blessings should prepare themselves by living worthily and striving to 
			be guided by the Holy Spirit. They should perform each ordinance or blessing in a dignified manner, making sure 
			it meets the following requirements: </p>

			<b>1.</b> It should be performed in the name of Jesus Christ. <br />
			<b>2.</b> It should be performed by the authority of the priesthood. <br />
			<b>3.</b> It should be performed with any necessary procedures, such as using specified words or using 
			consecrated oil.<br />
			<b>4.</b> It should be authorized by the presiding authority who holds the proper keys (normally the 
			bishop or stake president), if necessary according to the instructions in this chapter.
			
			<p>A priesthood leader who oversees an ordinance or blessing ensures that the person who performs it has the 
			necessary priesthood authority, is worthy, and knows and follows the proper procedures. Leaders also seek to 
			make the ordinance or blessing a reverent and spiritual experience.</p>

			<p>When ordinances or blessings are performed in sacrament meeting, the bishop ensures that they are performed 
			properly. To avoid embarrassing a priesthood holder, the bishop quietly corrects errors only if essential 
			elements of the ordinance or blessing are incorrect.</p>

			<p>Those who give priesthood blessings speak words of blessing (“I [or we] bless you that …”) rather than 
			saying a prayer (“Heavenly Father, please bless this person that …”).</p>

		]]>
    </string>
    
    <!-- Ordinance.java Strings -->
    <string name="error">An Error Has Occurred</string>
    
    <!-- about_lds.xml Strings -->
    <string name="alternate_text_on_about_lds">picture of application icon</string>
    <string name="version">Version</string>   <!-- version also used in about_lds.xml Strings -->
    <string name="copy_right">2012 Klapheck Apps</string>
    <string name="send_feedback">Send Feedback</string>
    
    <!-- about_lds.xml Strings -->   
    <string name="rate">From 1 to 10, I rate this app: </string>
    <string name="message">message:</string>
    
    <!-- MainMenu.java Strings -->
    <string name="discovered">I discovered LDS Ordinances.</string>
    
    <!-- open_source.xml Strings -->
    <string name="open_source_initiative">Source</string>
    <string name="open_source_title">References</string>
    
    <!-- OpenSource.java Strings -->
    <string name="open_source_logo_discription">Open Source Initiative logo</string>
    <string name="java_source">Java source code</string>
    <string name="lds_org">LDS.org - content</string>
    <string name="app_icon">Application icon source</string>
    <string name="lds_info">LDS Info (Android App - inspiration)</string>
    <string name="lds_priesthood_ord">LDS Priesthood Ordinances (iPhone App - inspiration)</string>
    
    <!-- main_menu.xml Strings -->
    <string name="about_us">About Us</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="blessings">Blessings</string>
    <string name="open_source">Open-Source</string>
    <string name="exit">Exit</string>
    
    <!-- blessings_action_menu.xml Strings -->
    <string name="move_up">Move Up</string>
    <string name="move_down">Move Down</string>
    <string name="default_order">Default Order</string>
    
    <!-- blessings_menu.xml Strings -->
    <string name="enlarge_text">Enlarge Text</string>
    
    <!-- Ordinance.java Strings -->
    <string name="text_small">Small</string>
    <string name="text_medium">Medium</string>
    <string name="text_large">Large</string>
    <string name="text_default">Default</string>

</resources>